Mss.Ms.Coll.109
American Philosophical Society
- Works By, 12.75 linear feet
  - Smiling, Notes, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Smoking, Notes, undated; 1 item (Box 81)
  - Social Brain Damage, Draft, 1973; 3 items (Box 82)
    Two negatives taken from correspondence and placed in Series XI.
  - Social Change and Human Change, Draft, 1964; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Social Impacts of Unnecessary Intervention and Unnatural Surroundings in Childbirth, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Social Treatment of the Aged, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Sociobiology Examined, Reviews, 1981; 5 items (Box 82)
  - Sociogenic Brain Damage, Correspondence, 1971; 1972; 4 items (Box 82)
  - Sociogenic Brain Damage, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Sociogenic Brain Damage, Reviews, undated; 2 items (Box 82)
  - Sociogenic Illness, Notes, 1938; 1993-1996; undated; 15 items (Box 82)
  - Some Factors in Family Cohesion, 1944; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Speech, Notes, undated; 9 items (Box 82)
  - A Spurious Portrait of Robert Hooke (1635-1703), Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Statement on Race, Third Edition, Galley Copy, 1972; 1 item (Box 120)
    Item removed to Oversize, Box 120
  - Statement on Race, Reviews, 1951; 1952; 17 items (Box 82)
  - Statement on Race- A Generation of Scientific Study, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Straight Talk About Breastfeeding, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Stress, Strain, and Structure in the Human Thigh-Bone, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 82)
  - A Study of Man Embracing Error, Draft, 1947; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Study of Man Embracing Error- Or Anthropology and Self-Deception, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Summary of Part II on Sexual Selection in the Lower Classes of the Animal Kingdom, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Swanscombe Archaeological Activity, Notes, 1948; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Swanscombe Archaeological Activity, Correspondence, 1947-1950; 85 items (Box 82)
  - Swanscombe Archaeological Activity, Misc., 1948; undated; 11 items (Box 82)
  - Sweat and Body Odor, Draft, 1966; 1 item (Box 82)
  - The Symbolism of Color, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Technology, Notes, undated; 13 items (Box 82)
  - Technology, Culture, and Telecommunication, Outline, undated; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Television, Notes, undated; 3 items (Box 82)
  - Television, Correspondence, 1981; 1990; 2 items (Box 82)
  - Terminal Man, Draft, 1983; 1 item (Box 82)
  - Textbook on Human Genetics, Notes, undated; 312 items (Box 82)
  - Textbook on Human Genetics, Correspondence, 1969-1973, 86 items (Box 82)
  - Textbook on Human Genetics, Correspondence, 1965-1968, 1965-1968; undated; 111 items (Box 82)
  - Textbook on Human Genetics, Chapter 3, Draft, 1966; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Textbook on Human Genetics, Chapter 4, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Textbook on Human Genetics, Chapter 14, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Textbook on Human Genetics, Chapter 20, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
    Chapter appears as Chapter 18 in the published text, but Chapter 20 in the draft manuscript.
  - Textbook on Human Genetics, Reviews, 1972; 23 items (Box 83)
  - Therapy, Nudism and Joy, Foreword, Draft, 1990; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Therapy, Nudity, Partial Draft, 1990; 1 item (Box 83)
  - "There has been a revolution in America. A complete change in our ways of thinking about parentage," Draft, 1980; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Thinking, Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 83)
  - Thomas Wise, Correspondence, 1920; 1934; 1978; 8 items (Box 83)
  - Thomas Wise, Draft, 1986; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Thumbsucking, Notes, undated; 9 items (Box 83)
  - Thumbsucking, Correspondence, 1937; 1942; 2 items (Box 83)
  - "To be born human is to be born in danger...," Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - To Be or Not to Be? Annihilation or Perpetual Peace?, Draft, 1984; 1 item (Box 83)
  - To Boris Pasternak, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - To Drink or Not to Drink?, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - To Smoke or Not to Smoke?, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Toolmaking, Hunting, and the Origin of Language, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Tools, Notes, undated; 2 items (Box 83)
  - Tools, Correspondence, 1973-1990; undated; 12 items (Box 83)
  - Touch: The First of the Senses, Draft, 1981; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Touching Dialogue, Foreword, Correspondence, 1988; 1989; 2 items (Box 83)
  - Townsend, Notes, undated; 4 items (Box 83)
  - Townsend, Introduction, Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 83)
  - Toynbee and Super-History, Correspondence, 1955; 1956; 31 items (Box 83)
  - Toynbee and Super-History, Partial Draft, undated; 2 items (Box 83)
  - "Trobriand Islanders of the north-western South Pacific," Partial Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Twin Bulletin, Draft, 1941; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Twins- Genetics, Scientific Method and the Relation of Criminal Behavior to Zygosity, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Two Talks on Persuasion, Draft, 1957; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Two Views of Coon's Origin of Races, Draft, 1963; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Tyson's Orang-Outang, Sive Homo Sylvestris and Swfit's Gulliver's Travels, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - The Unacknowledged Legislators of the World, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Understanding Our Sexual Desires, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - UNESCO Statement on Race, 2nd Edition, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Unidentified Outline, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Unidentified Partial Manuscripts, undated; 9 items (Box 83)
  - University and Community, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - The Urge to Acquire Kids, Draft, 1980; 1 item (Box 83)
  - The Variability of Man, Notes, undated; 8 items (Box 83)
  - Verbal Violence, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - A Version of Man, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Veteran's Administration, Class Materials, 1947; 1948; undated; 8 items (Box 83)
  - Vietnam War, Notes, undated; 1 item (Box 83)
  - Vulgar Errors, Original Manuscript, 1 of 2, undated; 1 item (Box 83a)
  - Vulgar Errors, Original Manuscript, 2 of 2, undated; 1 item (Box 83a)
  - Vulgar Errors, Notes, undated; 34 items (Box 84)
  - Vulgar Errors, Draft, 1 of 2, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Vulgar Errors, Draft, 2 of 2, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Wallbrook Frontal Bone, Notes, undated; 4 items (Box 84)
  - Wallbrook Frontal Bone, Correspondence, 1950; 2 items (Box 84)
  - The Wallbrook Frontal Bone, Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 84)
  - The Wallbrook FrontaL Bone and the Swanscombe Parietal, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - The Ways of Prejudice, Draft, 1958; 1 item (Box 84)
  - "Weeping is defined as the expression or manifestation of sorrow...," Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Weeping, Notes, undated; 3 items (Box 84)
  - Weeping, Correspondence, 1960; 1982; 9 items (Box 84)
  - What Ever Happened to the Cradle?, Notes, undated; 5 items (Box 84)
  - What Ever Happened to the Cradle?, Correspondence, 1962; 1967; undated; 9 items (Box 84)
  - What Ever Happened to the Cradle?, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - What is Human Biology?, Draft, See note; 1 item (Box 84)
    Possibly from 1940. Has 1940? in top right corner.
  - What is Skin Color, Draft, 1947; 1 item (Box 84)
  - What Marriage Means to a Man, Draft, 1969; 2 items (Box 84)
    Two different versions.
  - What Women Think, Correspondence, 1954; undated; 12 items (Box 84)
  - "When in March 1665 Henry Oldenburgh began..., " Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Who Dominates Who?, Draft, 1963; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Who Really Rules the Family, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Why Babies Should Be Breast-Fed, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - 'Why Dominates Who,' Draft, 1964; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Why is Man Born in so Immature a State?, Draft, 1960; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Why Man Laughs, Draft, 1960; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Will Our Civil RIghts Be Destroyed by Legislation Against Minority Groups?, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - A Womb with a View, Foreword, Drafts, 1991; 2 items (Box 84)
  - Women, Correspondence, 1953-1962; 30 items (Box 84)
  - Women, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Women in Books, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Women's Emotion and Their Behavior, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Work is Pleasure, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - "world of humanity is in a very precarious state," Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
    "Introduction for Amemiya's booklet" written on the bottom of the sheet.
  - Your Back and Its Troubles, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
  - Your Greatest Gift to Your Child, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 84)
- Media Appearances, 1.25 linear feet
  Series IV consists of correspondence, transcripts and ephemera from Montagu’s appearances on television and radio, as well as his many speaking engagements. The bulk of the material is from the 1980s, when Montagu was most active.
  - Radio Appearances, Transcripts, 1950; 1953; 1962; 3 items (Box 85)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, 1990s, 1990-1998; 11 items (Box 85)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, 1989, 33 items (Box 85)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, 1988, 75 items (Box 85)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, 1987, 60 items (Box 85)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, 1986, 90 items (Box 85)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, 1985, 100 items (Box 85)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, 1984, 90 items (Box 85)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, 1983, 70 items (Box 86)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, 1980-1982, 160 items (Box 86)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, 1970s, 1970-1979; 56 items (Box 86)
  - Speaking Engagements, Correspondence, 1930s-1960s and undated, 1938-1969; undated; 31 items (Box 86)
  - Speaking Engagements, Misc, undated; 93 items (Box 86)
    5 lecture posters removed to Oversize, Box 119.
    Includes various ephemera from Montagu's many speaking engagements, including fliers, programs and itineraries from conferences and appearances.
  - Television Appearances, Correspondence, 1954-1983, 271 items (Box 87)
  - Television Appearances, Correspondence, Undated, 72 items (Box 87)
  - Television Appearances, "Science, Please" Program Proposal, undated; 1 item (Box 87)
- Princeton, 0.5 linear feet
  Series V is made up of material from Montagu’s time at Princeton University. While not a professor there, Montagu served many years as a lecturer and a fellow at Princeton’s Stevenson Hall. The series consists of class materials, student evaluations, and correspondence to and from the University, the Stevenson Hall administration, and the Library Advisory Council, on which Montagu served.
  - Anthropology Course Materials, 1978-1983; undated; 57 items (Box 88)
  - Anthropology Department Correspondence, 1977-1984; 67 items (Box 88)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1992; undated; 70 items (Box 88)
  - Library Advisory Council, 1979; 5 items (Box 88)
  - Stevenson Hall, 1982-1992; 38 items (Box 88)
    Includes correspondence, newsletters and hall yearbooks.
  - Student Evaluations, 1983; undated; 100 items (Box 88)
  - Miscellaneous, 1979-1982; undated; 83 items (Box 88)
- Works By Others, 5.0 linear feet
  Series VI is comprised of works by others, and greatly reflects Montagu’s varied interests: racial and social equality, women’s rights, child development, humanistic psychology and genetics. These interests are represented by the works of many influential people in the aforementioned fields, such as Henry Louis Gates Jr., Theodosius Dobzhansky, Mary S. Calderone, J.B.S. Haldane, Arthur Jensen, A.H. Maslow, Benjamin Pasamanick and many others. Montagu remained well read in the works of those authors he did not always agree with, especially the racial and eugenic theories of men like Jensen and Haldane, so while the series does not accurately reflect the entirety of Montagu’s opinions, it is a great resource for discovering his sphere of interest.
  - AAA Film Index, Set 1, undated; 4 items (Box 89)
  - Adams, David and Sarah Bosch, The Myth That War is Intrinsic to Human Nature Discourages Action for Peace by Young People, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
    See also, Series I: Adams, David.
  - Adelberg, Michael, The Neotenic Brain, 1996; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Adelberg, Michael, The Professor's Library, 1980; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Alexander Rae, The History of Narcotics, 1965; 1 item (Box 89)
  - American Medical Association, A Reappraisal of Eugenic Sterilization Laws, 1960; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Askenasy, Hans, Are We All Nazis?, 1997; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Augier, M., Skull and Brain in the Aged, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Augier, M., Summary statement of "Crane et Corveau chez les Viellards", undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Babinski, Edward T., Is 'Selfish DNA' a Mythical Beast?, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Babinski, Edward T., Serious, Selfish DNA, 1 item (Box 89)
  - Bachicha, Carol, The Influence of a Teacher's Affective Sensitivity on the Development of the Student, 1978; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Barnes, T.C., The Terror of Loneliness, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Bateson, Gregory, Form, Substance, and Difference, 1970; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Beidelman, T.O., A Bibliography of the Writings of E.E. Evans-Pritchard, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Bell, Ralph P., Mount Allison University Mourns the Death of One of its Most Distinguished Graduates, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Berger, F.M., Anxiety and Its Treatment, 1965; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Berger, F.M., The Drugs of the Future, 1971; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Bernier, Francois, New Division of the Earth, According to the Different Species or Races of Men Who Inhabit it, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Bhaumik, M.L., The Unified Field, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Bloch, M.A., Philip Guedalla: A Sketch for a Biography, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Booth, Edwin, Moral Values and the Study of Biography, 1956; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Bostock, John, Exterior Gestation, Primitive Sleep, Enuresis and Asthma: A Study in Ætiology, 1958; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Boyle, Joan and James Morris, The Mirror of Time: Images of Aging and Dying, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Bradley, Robert, Father's Place During Childbirth, 1966; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Brophy, Truman, Anatomy of the Palate, Normal and Cleft, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Brower, Jonathan, The Racial Basis of the Division of Labor Among Players in the National Football League as a Function of Racial Stereotypes, 1972; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Bulmash, Rebecca, Depression in Women and Its Diagnosis, 1984; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Burger, Henry G., Behavior Modification and Operant Psychology: An Anthropological Critique, 1969; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Burston, Dan, Eric Fromm: A Critical Appreciation, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
    Dissertation Proposal
  - Cairns, Robert, et al., On Fighting in Mice: Is There A Sensitive Period for Isolation Effects?, 1984; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Calderone, Mary S., Adolescent Sexual Behavior: Whose Responsibility?, 1964; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Calderone, Mary S., Sex and the Teenager- and the Physician, 1965; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Cameron, Paul, Frequency and Kinds of Profanity in Various Social Settings, 1969; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Cameron, Paul, The Language of College Students, or Damn all Over, undated; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Cella, Catherine, A Conversation with Dr. Ashley Montagu: Communicating with Your Newborn, 1988; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Chass, Allan, Academic Accountability: The Need for Training in Skeptical Scrutiny, 1977; 1 item (Box 89)
  - Cole, John, Scopes and Beyond: Antievolutionism and American Culture, 1982; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Conrad, Jack, The Many Worlds of Man, 1964; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Cooke, Bernard, Responsibility of Religious Communities, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Coppock-Groe, C.K., The Touch of Teacher, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Cox, Harvey, The Urban Mentality, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Craig, Archibald, Mammon, 1955; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Danna, Louis J., The Invention of the Telephone, 1989; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Dart, Raymond A., A Tribute to Reginald Ruggles Gates, 1966; 1 item (Box 90)
  - DeMeo, James, The Origins and Diffusion of Patrism in Saharasia, 1987; 1 item (Box 90)
  - DeYoung, Mary Jane, I am a Teenaged Athiest, 1966; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Dobkin, Marlene, Folk Curing with a Psychedelic Cactus in the North Coast of Peru, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, The Genetic Nature of Differences Among Men, 1950; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, Review of Race, a Study in Superstition, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Doherty, Sue, Kinergetics, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Dooley, Denis, Wakes & Weddings, 1989; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Edwards, J. Gordon, A New Approach to Intraspecific Categories, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Einstein, Albert, Cosmic Religion, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Eisler, Raine, The Chalice and the Blade, undated; 10 items (Box 90)
  - Eisler, Raine, The Gylan Future, Proposal, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Eisler, Raine, Souls, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Eisler, Riane and David Loye, Prediction in the Dream Factory, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Elkes, Joel, Discussion, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Elkes, Joel, Letter to a Young Colleague Considering a Career in Psychopharmacology, 1977; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Elkes, Joel, On Awareness and the Good Day, 1979; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Elkes, Joel, Self-Regulation and Behavioral Medicine: A Continuing Tradition at Johns Hopkins, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Emerson, Alfred, The Impact of Darwin on Biology, 1958; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Etkin, William, The Religious Meaning of Contemporary Science, 1963; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Eyman, Frances, Australian Warfare, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Farris, Edmond, Permanent Preservation of the Human Body by Infiltration, 1932; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Fergueson, R. Brian, Violence and War in Prehistory, 1996; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Fight On, Ashley Montagu: Study of a Communist-Socialist Propagandist in "Anthropology", 1967; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Foote, Nelson, Family Living as Play, 1955 (Box 90)
  - Frank, Leonard Roy, Testimony at the San Francisco Board of Supervisors' Third Electroshock Hearing, 1991; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Freudenberger, Herbert J., Treatment and Dynamics of the "Disrealated" Teenager and his Parents in the American Society, 1969; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Frey, William, et al., Crying Behavior in the Human Adult, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Frost, Peter, Sexual Dimorphism in Human Skin Colour and the Origins of Colour Prejudice, undated; 1 item (Box 90)
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster, Address to the American Institute of Planners, St. Louis, Missouri, October 18, 1965, 1 item (Box 90)
  - Fuller, R. Buckminster, Vision 65, October 1965, 1 item (Box 90)
  - Galt, Alfreda, Tigant Burrow and the Laboratory of the "I", undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Garrett, Henry E., Comparison of Negro and White Recruits on the Army Tests Given in 1917-1918, 1945; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gates, Henry Louis, Jr., Race, Writing, and Difference, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gates, R. Ruggles and P.N. Bhaduri, The Inheritance of Hairy Ear Rims, 1961; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gerard, Ralph, Fate and Freedom: A Review and Rejoinder, 1946; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gerard, Ralph, Final Summary, 1958; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gerard, Ralph, How the Brain Creates Ideas, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gilbert, Stuart, trans., Why War? A Correspondence between Albert Einstein and Sigmund Freud, 1933; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gilman, Lawrence, Music and the Cultivated Man, 1929; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gimbutas, Marija, Pre Patriarchal Religion, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Goldberg, Isadore, Incidence of Sicklemia, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Goldstein, Marcus, Anthropology and Medical Care, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Goodenough, Erwin, Religious Scholarship in a Modern University, 1946; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gordon, Sol, Sense and Nonsense About Brain Injury and Learning Disabilities, 1970; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gorney, Roderic, The Ashley Montagu Humankind Library, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gorney, Roderic, Of Divers Things: Preliminary Note on the Dynamics of Scuba Diving, 1966; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gorney, Roderic, On Being Human: A Day With Ashley Montagu, 1988; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gorney, Roderic, Hope for Humankind, 1996; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Green, Morris and Patricia Bell, Paternal Deprivation- A Disturbance in Fathering, 1962; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Gruenwald, Bjorn J., Statement before the United States House of Representatives Interior and Insular Affairs Subcommittee, 1992; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Haldane, JBS, Anthropology and Human Biology, 1934; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Haldane, JBS, Mathematical Notes, 1951; 2 items (Box 91)
  - Hanna, Judith, Identity, Defiance, and "Race" Relations: Children's Spontaneous Dance in Urban Education, 1980; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Hanna, Judith, Is Dance Music? Resemblances and Relationships, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Hanna, Judith, Patterns of Dominance in Gender Images and Their Production, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Hanna, Judith, Patterns of Dominance in Sexual Images and Their Production, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
    Abstract
  - Hanna, Judith, The Performer-Audience Connection: Feeling in Dance and Society, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Hanna, Judith, Project Description, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Hanna, Judith, The Representation and Reality of Divinity in Dance, 1985; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Hanna, Judith, "Truth," Constraints, and Consequence, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Hanson, Jarice, Technological Psychosis and Human Values, 1985; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Hardin, Garrett, Abortion and Human Dignity, 1964; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Harding, D.W., Values in an Industrial Society, 1956; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Haronian, Frank, Physique and Learning: An Exploratory Study, 1963; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Hartman, Robert, Research in Values, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Helmuth, H., Cannibalism, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Hemschemeyer, Judith, trans., Poems of Anna Andreyevna Akhmatova, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Herbert, Emil, Classification and Pathogenesis of Malformations of the Dental Lamina, undated; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Herter, Christian, et al., Readings on Population Growth and Brith Control, 1965; 1 item (Box 91)
  - Hilliard, Constance, The Phallic Equation: Gender, Race and the Unspoken Variable in IQ Research, undated; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Hirsh, Jerry and Atam Vetta, The Misconceptions of Behavior Genetics, undated; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Hirsh, Jerry, To "Unfrock the Charlatans", 1981; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Howard, Thomas C., An Experimental College, 1965; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Hrdlicka, Ales, Anthropological Investigations, 1900; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Hudson, Liam, The Choice of Hercules, 1970; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Hudson, Liam, Intelligence and Scientism, 1972; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Hudson, Liam, The Tyranny of the Fact, 1972; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Hungerford, Mary Jane, The Pitfalls of Teenage Marriage, 1967; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Huxley, Aldous, "Dr. Ashley Montagu's pamphlet...", undated; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Inman, Verne and John B. de C.M. Saunders, The Ossification of the Human Frontal Bone, 1937; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Jensen, Arthur, Preface to Genetics and Education, 1972; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Jensen, Arthur, Skinner and Human Differences, undated; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Jensen, Arthur, Lectures and Speeches, 1971; 1972; 2 items (Box 92)
  - Jewish Folk Songs, undated; 7 items (Box 92)
  - Johnson, Amy, Play It Where the Sun Shines, undated; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Juzwiak, Marijo, An Intimate Look at Husband-Coached Childbirth, 1966; 1 item (Box 92)
  - Kahn, Carol, Ashley Montagu, undated; 1 item (Box 93)
  - Kalikow, T.J., Konrad Lorenz's Account of Human "Domestication" Phenomena: Explanation and Ideology, 1938-1954, 1977; 1 item (Box 93)
  - Kalikow, T.J., Konrad Lorenz's Ethological Theory: Explanation and Ideology, 1938-1943, 1980; 2 items (Box 93)
  - Kallen, Horace, M., The Modern World, the Intellectual and William James, undated; 1 item (Box 93)